<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./predict.png" type="Predictor" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>DL4J Feedforward Predictor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Predictor for Feedforward Deep Learning Models.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node uses the supplied trained Deep Learning Model to create predictions or activations for the supplied
        test data. The network output activation will be appended to the training data as a collection column where the collection
        has the same length as the number of output units of the network, which is usually specified in the Output Layer. The numbers 
        contained in the collection are the raw output activations of the last layer of the network. If specified and the activation of 
        the last layer is 'softmax' the raw activation can be interpreted as class probabilities and be associated with a class label 
        taken from the Deeplearning Model the model was trained on. The supplied data table needs to be in the same format as the table 
        used for learning, meaning it needs to contain columns of the same name and type.</intro>
            
        <option name="Append softmax prediction">
        Whether to append the predicted label to the output table. This is only possible if the output layer of the network
        configuration uses softmax activation function. The label with the highest corresponding softmax probability will
        be chosen.
        </option>       
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Deep Learning Model">Trained Deep Learning Model.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Data Table">Data table containing testing data.</inPort>
        
        <outPort index="0" name="Data Table">Data Table containing original testing data with appended network output.
        The network output is given by a collection column containing output activations for each test example. Additionally,
        softmax prediction may be appended.
        </outPort>      
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
